A Guide to the Papers of Melville C. Branch, Jr., 1914-2004
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Papers of Melville C. Branch, Jr. 1914-2004
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 327
12 linear feet and oversize materials.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Provenance
Donated to the Special Collections and Archives Department by Mr. Melville C. Branch, Jr. in 2003.
Biographical/Historical Information
Melville Campbell Branch, Jr. (1913-2008) pioneered consideration of planning as a distinct intellectual discipline and the subject of professional practice. He has the distinction of being the first person in the United States to receive an advanced degree in Planning: a Ph.D. in regional planning from Harvard University in 1949. He is the first person in the nation designated Distinguished Professor of Planning, by the University of Southern California. His nearly 60 years career includes work in academia, government, private enterprise, and the U.S. Navy.
In an unpublished 2003 essay entitled "Planning: Universal Process", Dr. Branch wrote that for "over fifty years, my thoughts, research, and working experiences have been directed to exploring and formulating in written form the fundamental nature and significance of the planning process as a law of human forethought and action." He concludes the essay by noting that planning has "shaped the human condition, subject to events beyond human influence. Aside from procreation, it is also the human activity which will most crucially affect our prospects as a society and our survival in an ever-changing world."
A long-time educator, researcher, and writer, Dr. Branch is the author of twenty-three books and over seventy-five professional papers relating to planning. His original contributions include the first books published on: corporate planning; sample surveys in city planning; the use of aerial photography and remote sensing in city and regional planning; and comprehensive planning theory and principles. Another three of his books expand on several elements of comprehensive planning: communication, simulation, and human behavior.
Born in Richmond, Virginia, on 16 February 1913, Dr. Branch is the eldest son of Melville Campbell and Martha (Bowie) Branch. He attended Princeton University (1930-1934) graduating as a Bachelor of Arts with high honors, and the Princeton University graduate college (1934-1936), receiving a two-year Master of Fine Arts in Architecture. In the summer of 1934, Dr. Branch studied at the Ecole des Beaux-Arts, Fontainebleau, France, and received a Diplome for a project in planning and design. From 1937-1938, Dr. Branch was a fellow at the Cranbrook Academy of Art in Bloomfield Hills, Michigan, where he completed independent research in city planning.
Dr. Branch headed the section designing the urban areas in the General Motors Futurama exhibit at the 1939 New York World's Fair. He was a Research Assistant at the U.S. National Resources Planning Board (NRPB) in the executive offices of President Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1939-1941. On leave from November 1940 - February 1941, Dr. Branch designed and directed the exhibit "The City" at the Baltimore Museum of Art, the largest city planning exhibit displayed in the United States to that date. He left the NRPB to become Director of the Bureau of Urban Research at Princeton University.
In 1943, Dr. Branch was commissioned Lieutenant JG in the U.S. Naval Reserve, assigned as an Instructor at the U.S. Naval Air Combat Intelligence School. He taught "maps and photographs" and wrote a flack information bulletin circulated in the Pacific Ocean area. After three years in the Navy, he spent a year at Harvard enrolled for the Ph.D. degree in planning. From 1947 until 1951, Dr. Branch was an Associate Professor in the Graduate Program of Education and Research in Planning at the University of Chicago.
In 1951, Dr. Branch left Chicago for Los Angeles, California, becoming an Intelligence Officer at the Los Angeles Office of the U.S. Central Intelligence Agency. In 1954, he became Corporate Associate for Planning and Member of the Senior Staff (West Coast) of the Ramo-Woolridge Corporation (RW). While there, he was appointed in 1961 to the Los Angeles Board of City Planning Commissioners, serving nine years as a member, vice president, and president. Dr. Branch was a Lecturer in Engineering (Planning) at the College of Engineering at the University of California at Los Angeles from 1962-1966.
Dr. Branch joined the faculty at the University of Southern California in 1966 as a Professor in the Planning Program within the School of Public Administration. The Program developed into a School of Urban and Regional Planning, and finally into a School of Policy, Planning, and Development. He taught half-time from 1984-1992 as a Professor Emeritus.
Dr. Branch has consulted briefly for Douglas Aircraft Company, Standard Oil Company of California, Southern California Edison Company, and during the summer of 1978, for the Department of Economic Development and Planning, Faculty of Economics and Management, at the National University of Malaysia.
In 1939, Dr Branch was awarded the Charlotte Elisabeth Proctor Fellowship for independent graduate study at Princeton University. In 1986, the Distinguished Leadership Award of the American Planning Association. In 2000, the Planning Educator Award of the Association of Collegiate Schools in Planning. In 2003, he was elected a Fellow in the American Institute of Certified Planners.
Dr. Branch was married to his second wife, Hilda S. Rollman-Branch, M.D., for over fifty years. Dr. Rollman-Branch came to the United States from German occupied territories in Europe during World War II. While in the United States, Dr. Rollman-Branch studied chemistry, medicine, psychiatry and psychoanalysis. She has served many notable appointments in the Los Angeles Psychoanalytic Society and Institute (LAPSI) and the American Psychoanalytical Association (APsaA).
Melville Campbell Branch, Jr died on February 11, 2008 while living in Pacific Palisades, California. He was 94 years old.
Scope and Content
The materials in this collection range from 1914 to 2004 and include correspondence, drawings, photographs, and numerous publications by Dr. Branch and others. The collection documents his early life, mostly through correspondence with other family members, and his entire academic career. Most of these documents concern Dr. Branch's professional accomplishments in the field of architecture, urban planning, and design. The collection is highlighted by Branch's artwork displayed in scrapbooks, portfolios, and oversized handmade books concerning the General Motors Futurama at the 1939 World's Fair, the Baltimore Museum exhibition "The City," and architectural and urban planning designs for Richmond's bicentennial celebration in 1937 - two hundred years after the city was founded by William Byrd.
His more than fifty years of research and writing concerning comprehensive planning as a universal process are represented in the collection by twelve of his books and various papers specifically devoted to this subject.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically by the major periods of Dr. Branch's personal and professional life.
Contents List
- Personal
  - Birth Records 1914 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Branchiana 1920, 1941, 1996, n.d. (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Correspondence, Family, Miscellaneous 1924, 1925, 1933 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Correspondence, Family, M.I. Branch (Grandfather) 1924, 1925 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Correspondence, Family, Melville C. Branch Sr. (Father) 1915, 1922-1924 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Correspondence, Family, Mate (Sister) 1923, 1924, n.d. (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Correspondence, Family, Granny 1923, 1925, n.d. (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Correspondence, Family, Martha Patterson Bowie (Mother) 1923-1925, 1932, n.d. (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Correspondence, Family, Melville C. Branch Jr. to Martha Patterson Bowie (Mother) 1932, 1933, n.d. (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Correspondence, Family, Hilda Branch (Wife) 1949, 1950, 1994, n.d. (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Divorce Papers 1950 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Marriage Records 1939/1946 (1 of 3) (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Marriage Records 1939 (2 of 3) (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Marriage Records 1939 (3 of 3) (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Photographs, Melville C. Branch 1982, n.d. (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Photographs, Melville C. Branch with Friends 1996, 1997, n.d. (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Vitae 1924, 1951, 1993, 2002, n.d. (Box-folder 1:18)
- Princeton University 1930-1934, 1934-1937
  - Commencement Book 1934 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Correspondence 1934, 1936, 1938, 1939 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Correspondence, Binder from Letters to Mother n.d (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Correspondence, Letters to Mother n.d., 1930 (1 of 2) (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Correspondence, Letters to Mother n.d., 1930 (2 of 2) (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Correspondence, Letters to Mother n.d., 1931 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Coursework n.d., 1932, 1933 - in Box 6 (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Miscellaneous n.d., 1982 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Project n.d. (ca. 1934) (Box-folder 1:27)
  - Transcripts 1930-1937 (Box-folder 1:28)
- Fontainebleau, Ecole des Beau-Arts, Paris, France 1934
  - Fontainebleau, Ecole des Beau-Arts, Paris, France 1934 (Box-folder 1:29)
- Richmond Preview Exhibit 1937
  - Richmond Preview Exhibit 1937 (Box-folder 1:30)
- Cranbrook Academy of Art 1937-1938
  - Correspondence (ca.1937-1938), 1936-1938, 1940, n.d. (Box-folder 1:31)
  - Coursework (ca. 1937-1938), 1937, 1938, n.d. (Box-folder 1:32)
  - Design for an Efficient Fork (Photocopy of original that was returned to Mr. Branch with the fork) 1937 (Box-folder 1:33)
  - Journal Clippings 1930, 1939, 1980, 1984, 1989 - in Box 6 (Box-folder 1:34)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1984 - in Box 6 (Box-folder 1:35)
  - Photographs n.d. (1 of 5) (Box-folder 1:36)
  - Photographs n.d. (2 of 5) (Box-folder 1:37)
  - Photographs n.d. (3 of 5) (Box-folder 1:38)
  - Photographs n.d. (4 of 5) (Box-folder 1:39)
  - Photographs n.d. (5 of 5) (Box-folder 1:40)
- Harvard 1946-1947
  - Correspondence 1949, 1996, 2002 (Box-folder 1:41)
  - Grade Report 1946-1947 (Box-folder 1:42)
  - Miscellaneous Illustration, Robinson Hall n.d. (Box-folder 1:43)
  - Report, A Special Investigation of North Kingstown, Rhode Island n.d. (Box-folder 1:44)
  - Xerox of Ph.D. Degree n.d. (Box-folder 1:45)
- United States Navy and United States Naval Reserve 1945-1946
  - Anti-Aircraft Intelligence 1944, n.d. (Box-folder 1:46)
  - Award Certificates 1942, n.d. (Box-folder 1:47)
  - Correspondence 1940-1942 (Box-folder 1:48)
  - Correspondence 1942-1943 (Box-folder 1:49)
  - Correspondence 1943-1945, 1952 (Box-folder 1:50)
  - Miscellaneous 1943-1944, n.d. (Box-folder 1:51)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1944-1945 (Box-folder 1:52)
  - Photographs (General) n.d. (Box-folder 1:53)
  - Photographs, AA n.d. (Box-folder 1:54)
  - Photographs, AA/Miyakojima/Others n.d. (Box-folder 1:55)
  - Photographs, Hamburg n.d. (Box-folder 1:56)
  - Photographs, Iwojima/Others n.d. (Box-folder 1:57)
  - Photographs, Miscellaneous n.d. (Box-folder 1:58)
  - Photographs, Target Material n.d. (Box-folder 1:59)
  - Reports 1943-1944, n.d. (Box-folder 1:60)
  - Reports 1944 (Box-folder 1:61)
  - Reports 1944-1945 (Box-folder 1:62)
- Norman Bel Geddes and Co. George Wittbold Inc.; General Motors Exhibit "Futurama", World's Fair 1939
  - Correspondence 1939 (Box-folder 1:63)
  - Drawings and Notes 1938, 1939, n.d. (Box-folder 1:64)
  - Journal Clippings 1939 (Box-folder 1:65)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1938 (Box-folder 1:66)
  - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 1:67)
  - Postcards n.d. (Box-folder 1:68)
  - Report n.d. (Box-folder 1:69)
- United States National Resources Planning Board (1939-1941)
  - Correspondence 1940-1942, n.d. (Box-folder 1:70)
  - Correspondence 1938-1940, n.d. (Box-folder 1:71)
  - Journal Clippings 1941 (Box-folder 1:72)
  - Local Planning, Progress Report 1940 (Box-folder 1:73)
  - Miscellaneous 1940-1941, n.d. (Box-folder 1:74)
  - Photographs 1939, 1940 (Box-folder 1:75)
  - Reports 1939, 1941 (Box-folder 1:76)
- Baltimore Museum of Art "The City" (1940-1941)
  - Announcements 1941 (Box-folder 1:77)
  - Correspondence 1940-1941, n.d. (Box-folder 1:78)
  - Newspaper Clippings (ca. 1940-1941), n.d. (Box-folder 1:79)
  - Notes 1940, 1941, n.d. (Box-folder 1:80)
  - Photographs (ca. 1940-1941), n.d. (Box-folder 1:81)
- Bureau of Urban Research, Princeton School of Architecture (1941-1943)
  - Correspondence 1939, 1940 (Box-folder 1:82)
  - Correspondence 1940, 1941, 1945, n.d. (Box-folder 1:83)
  - Journal Clippings 1941, 1943 (Box-folder 1:84)
  - Journal Excerpts 1941, 1942 (Box-folder 1:85)
  - Miscellaneous 1942, n.d. (Box-folder 1:86)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1942 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Publications, Bulletins, and Announcements 1940, 1941. 1942, n.d. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Reports 1940, 1941, 1942, n.d. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Reports and Proposals 1940, n.d. (Box-folder 2:5)
- University of Chicago (1947-1951)
  - Budgets 1948-1953, n.d. (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Correspondence n.d. (1 of 6) (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Correspondence 1947 (2 of 6) (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Correspondence 1948 (3 of 6) (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Correspondence 1949 (4 of 6) (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Correspondence 1950 (5 of 6) (Box-folder 2:11)
  - Correspondence 1951, 1952, 1953, 1955 (6 of 6) (Box-folder 2:12)
  - Course Material 1948-1950, n.d. (Box-folder 2:13)
  - Course Material 1950-1951, n.d. (Box-folder 2:14)
  - Lecture Notebook 1947-1950 (Box-folder 2:15)
  - Miscellaneous Publications and Excerpts 1947-1950, n.d. (Box-folder 2:16)
  - Reports 1948-1950 (Box-folder 2:17)
- CIA/RAND Corporation (1951-1954)
  - Correspondence 1950-1955, n.d. (Box-folder 2:18)
  - Reports 1951, n.d. (Box-folder 2:19)
- Thompson Ramo Woolridge (1954-1962)
  - Benefits and Insurance Papers 1954, 1955 (Box-folder 2:20)
  - Correspondence 1944?, 1954, 1955, 1956, 1958-1961, n.d. (Box-folder 2:21)
  - Journal and Newspaper Clippings 1954, 1955, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 2:22)
  - Miscellaneous 1954, 1955, 1959, n.d. (Box-folder 2:23)
  - Miscellaneous Notebook 1 (ca 1954-1962) (1 of 2), n.d. (Box-folder 2:24)
  - Miscellaneous Notebook 1 (ca 1954-1962) (2 of 2), n.d. (Box-folder 2:25)
  - Miscellaneous Notebook 2 (ca 1954-1962), n.d. (Box-folder 2:26)
  - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 2:27)
  - Photographs 1956- in Box 6 (Box-folder 2:28)
  - Project; Corporate Planning Illustrations 1961, n.d. (Box-folder 2:29)
  - Reports n.d. (Box-folder 2:30)
  - Reports 1954 (Box-folder 2:31)
  - Reports 1955 (1 of 3) (Box-folder 2:32)
  - Reports 1955 (2 of 3) (Box-folder 2:33)
  - Reports 1955 (3 of 3) (Box-folder 2:34)
  - Reports 1958, 1959, 1961 (Box-folder 2:35)
- Los Angeles City Planning Commission (1961-1970)
  - Correspondence 1962-1968, 1970 (Box-folder 2:36)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1965, 1978, n.d. (Box-folder 2:37)
  - Photographs 1966-1967, n.d. (Box-folder 2:38)
  - Reports and Proposals 1968, 1969, n.d. (Box-folder 2:39)
- Douglas Air Craft Company (1962-1964)
  - Douglas Air Craft Company (1962-1964) (Box-folder 2:40)
- University of Southern California (1966-1997)
  - Correspondence 1966, 1971-1973, 1981, 1983-1984, 1986-1987, 1989, 1991-1992, 1996-1997, n.d. (Box-folder 2:41)
  - Course Exercise n.d. (Box-folder 2:42)
  - Courses Given; Notebook 1 1966-1979 (1 of 3) (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Courses Given; Notebook 1 1966-1979 (2 of 3) (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Courses Given; Notebook 1 1966-1979 (3 of 3) (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Courses Given; Notebook 2 1968-1978 (1 of 3) (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Courses Given; Notebook 2 1968-1978 (2 of 3) (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Courses Given; Notebook 2 1968-1978 (3 of 3) (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1966, 1967, 1971, 1974, 1978, 1979, n.d. (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1980-1983, 1986, 1992, 1994 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Press Releases 1966, 1973 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Miscellaneous 1972, 1984-1986, 1990-1991, 1997, n.d. (Box-folder 3:11)
  - Proposals n.d. (Box-folder 3:12)
  - Proposals 1971-1972 (Box-folder 3:13)
  - Proposals 1973-1974 (Box-folder 3:14)
  - Proposals 1978 (1 of 2)- in Box 6 (Box-folder 3:15)
  - Proposals 1978 (2 of 2) - in Box 6 (Box-folder 3:16)
  - Reports 1960, 1969, 1972 (Box-folder 3:17)
  - Reports 1978- in Box 6 (Box-folder 3:18)
  - Reports 1981, 1982, 1990 (Box-folder 3:19)
  - Tugwell Award 1987 (Box-folder 3:20)
- American Institute of Certified Planners
  - American Institute of Certified Planners 1954, 1959, 1963, 1977, 1999, 2000, n.d. (Box-folder 3:21)
- American Society of Planning Officials
  - American Society of Planning Officials 1964, 1966, 1968, n.d. (Box-folder 3:22)
- American Planning Association
  - American Planning Association 1979, 1980, 1992, 2001 (Box-folder 3:23)
- Miscellaneous
  - Announcements n.d. (1 of 2) (Box-folder 3:24)
  - Announcements n.d. (2 of 2) (Box-folder 3:25)
  - Awards n.d. - in Box 6 (Box-folder 3:26)
  - Awards 1937, 1940, 1943, 1948, 1957-1959, 1964, 1972, 1978-1981, 1986, 1991-1992, n.d. (Box-folder 3:27)
  - Computer Discs n.d. (Box-folder 3:28)
  - Computer Discs n.d. (Box-folder 3:29)
  - Computer Discs n.d. (Box-folder 3:30)
  - Computer Discs 1970, n.d. (Box-folder 3:31)
  - Computer Discs 1989 (Box-folder 3:32)
  - Computer Discs 1990 (Box-folder 3:33)
  - Copyright Agreements 1973, 1974, 1978, 1992, 1997, 1998, 1999 (Box-folder 3:34)
  - Correspondence 1939, 1952, 1954, 1959, n.d. (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Correspondence 1960-1963 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Correspondence 1964-1969 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Correspondence 1970-1979 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Correspondence 1980-1989 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Correspondence 1990-1999 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Correspondence 2001, 2002, 2004 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - Correspondence; Letters from Abroad 1976-1978 (Box-folder 4:8)
  - Correspondence; Reading File n.d. (Box-folder 4:9)
  - Correspondence; Reading File 1953, 1955 (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Correspondence; Reading File 1956 (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Correspondence; Reading File 1957 (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Correspondence; Reading File 1958 (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Correspondence; Reading File 1959 (Box-folder 4:14)
  - Correspondence; Reading File 1960-1961 (Box-folder 4:15)
  - Correspondence; Sierra Club Postcard Book 1993 (Box-folder 4:16)
  - Figures for Publication n.d. (Box-folder 4:17)
  - Grant Agreements 1968, 1975 (Box-folder 4:18)
  - Illustrations Planning and the Human Condition n.d. - in Box 6 (Box-folder 4:19)
  - Internet Book Queries 1998, 2002 (Box-folder 4:20)
  - Journal Clippings 1935, 1949, n.d. (Box-folder 4:21)
  - Journal Clippings 1949 (Box-folder 4:22)
  - Maps 1966, 1975, 1983 (Box-folder 4:23)
  - Manuscripts n.d. (Box-folder 4:24)
  - News Releases 1972-1974, 1978, 1981, 1983, 1985, 1990, 1992 (Box-folder 4:25)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1972, 1974, 1978, 1979, 1983, 1986, 1997 (Box-folder 4:26)
  - Notes and Quotes 1988-1991 (Box-folder 4:27)
  - Photographs (ca. 1935), n.d. (Box-folder 4:28)
  - Photographs 1936, n.d. (Box-folder 4:29)
  - Photographs; Thesis Prints 1941 (Box-folder 4:30)
  - Projects 1937, 1974, n.d. (Box-folder 4:31)
  - Publication Agreements 1964, 1974, 1977, 1979, 1980, 1982, 1984, 1986, 1988, 1990, 1992, 1995, 1997, n.d. (Box-folder 4:32)
  - Publications 1957, 1964 (Box-folder 4:33)
  - Publications 1979 (Box-folder 4:34)
  - Publications n.d.- in Box 6 (Box-folder 4:35)
  - Reports n.d. (Box-folder 4:36)
  - Royalty Statements 1989, 1999 (Box-folder 4:37)
  - Scenario for Expert Testimony 1976-1977, n.d. - in Box 6 (Box-folder 4:38)
  - Sketches 1981, n.d. (Box-folder 4:39)
  - Writings and Thoughts n.d. (Box-folder 4:40)
- Publications
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Canberra Planning and Development n.d. - in Box 6 (Box-folder 4:41)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Chapter Headings, Comprehensive Planning Theory and Principles n.d. (Box-folder 4:42)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Comparative Urban Design, Inquiry Responses n.d. (1 of 2) (Box-folder 4:43)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Comparative Urban Design, Inquiry Responses n.d. (2 of 2) (Box-folder 4:44)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Consulting n.d. (1 of 3) (Box-folder 4:45)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Consulting n.d. (2 of 3) (Box-folder 4:46)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Consulting n.d. (3 of 3) (Box-folder 4:47)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Notebook 1 n.d. (1 of 3) (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Notebook 1 n.d. (2 of 3) (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Notebook 1 n.d. (3 of 3) (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Notebook, General Plan Guidelines 1982, 1982 (1 of 2) (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Notebook, General Plan Guidelines 1982, 1982 (2 of 2) (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Notebook, General Plan Guidelines 1987, 1987 (1 of 3) (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Notebook, General Plan Guidelines 1987, 1987 (2 of 3) (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Notebook, General Plan Guidelines 1987, 1987 (3 of 3) (Box-folder 5:8)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Notebook, The Nation's Shifting Demographics n.d. (Box-folder 5:9)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Notebook, New Town Policies n.d. (Box-folder 5:10)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Notebook, Urban Design 1 n.d. (Box-folder 5:11)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Notebook, Urban Design 2 n.d. (Box-folder 5:12)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Notecards n.d. (1 of 2) (Box-folder 5:13)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Notecards n.d. (2 of 2) (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Planning; Activity, Institution n.d. (Box-folder 5:15)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Planning and Development of New Towns, Book 3 n.d. (1 of 3) (Box-folder 5:16)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Planning and Development of New Towns, Book 3 n.d. (2 of 3) (Box-folder 5:17)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Planning and Development of New Towns, Book 3 n.d. (3 of 3) (Box-folder 5:18)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Planning and Development of New Towns, Book 4 n.d. (1 of 2) (Box-folder 5:19)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Planning and Development of New Towns, Book 4 n.d. (2 of 2) (Box-folder 5:20)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Planning as Subject and Field n.d. (Box-folder 5:21)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Publication Announcement Award Documents n.d. (1 of 2) (Box-folder 5:22)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Publication Announcement Award Documents n.d. (2 of 2) (Box-folder 5:23)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; US Government Material n.d. (Box-folder 5:24)
  - Miscellaneous Notes; Superego Seminar 1975 (Box-folder 5:25)